All right, so in this
section then, we're going to
cover the PIMBOC guide
processes of schedule management.
So in PIMBOC then, so we're talking about
PIMBOC version 6 here, there are six
processes altogether in the Schedule
Management section.
So the very first process
then under planning, right, so
there's basically the six processes
covered under the planning
process group and
monitoring and controlling.
Very first one then is plan schedule
management.
Now, plan schedule management,
just like any plan management process,
we're planning how we're going to,
in this case, develop the schedule.
What are all the procedures
regarded to develop the schedule,
how we're going to develop it,
how we're going to monitor and
control the schedule,
and so on and so forth.
So the artifact that's created,
or the output, as PMI calls it in version
6, PIMBOV version 6,
the output of plan schedule
management, is the schedule
management plan, right?
So the artifact that's
created or the document
that's created is the
schedule management plan.
And there's a separate video on that,
the schedule management plan.
It's basically documenting how we're going
to develop the schedule.
And all the procedures around developing
the schedule and all the procedures
around, you know, what happens if we're
going behind schedule and so and so forth.
Now, the next process here is define
activities.
And in define activities,
This process is a continuation,
if you like, of the work
breakdown structure.
So in scope management, we create the work
breakdown structure, and the work
breakdown structure is decomposing your
project down to the work package.
So the lowest level is a work package.
It's here in schedule
management, right, and
specifically the PIMBOP
process called define activities.
While we further take each work package,
and decompose it
into individual activities.
And then, again, there's a separate video
on that.
So we'll talk about the difference between
a work package and an activity.
What is an activity versus the work
package?
We'll talk about that in that video.
Now, we've identified our activities.
Now, we need to sequence them.
Put them in the proper order.
And that's what the sequence activity
process refers to.
This is a starting activity.
this is the next activity this is the next
activity this activity is dependent on uh
you know the successor activity is
dependent on the predecessor activity and
so and so forth so these activities can be
running parallel right so we're putting
them in the proper order and essentially
creating a network diagram of all of our
different activities now each of these
activities are going to take a certain
time right certain time to perform a
length of time to perform and that's where
this activity duration
estimate comes in That's
this process called
Activity Duration Estimate.
So for each activity, how long do we think
it's going to take?
And there are various
estimating methods, which, again,
we are going to be discussing
in these subsequent videos.
And then now we can develop the overall
schedule, the schedule
for the overall project.
So up until now, right, notice define
activities, sequence activities,
estimate activity duration.
They're all at an activity level.
They've all got the word activity in
there.
They're all at an activity level,
whereas now developing the schedule is now
developing the schedule for the overall
project.
So these are all the activities that need
to be done.
This is a start date of the project.
And based on one of
these activities are going
to complete, this is the
end date of the project.
So developed schedule then refers to the
project as a whole.
And developed schedule really refers to
the critical path method and the network
diagramming that we're going to be
performing in the critical path.
So this is going to be
covered in Lesson 6, and
Lesson 6 then is Schedule
Management Part 2.
Now, in Monitoring Controlling there,
the process is Control Schedule.
And remember, what is monitoring
controlling?
Monitoring controlling is comparing actual
results to your plan.
So our actual results versus a plan when
it comes to the schedule, essentially
refers to the fact that, you know,
are we ahead of schedule or behind
schedule, how many activities have
completed, how many should have been
completed, right, and then how do we move
forward?
So that's all monitoring controlling,
that's all controlling the schedule.
So these are the basic processes then.
These are the six
processes, or the six PIMBOC
guide processes as it
relates to PIMBOC version 6.